Guide to the Engin Ozendes Collection of Ottoman photography AD.MC.012
New York University Abu Dhabi Library
- Smiling woman, holding her dark colored veil across her body with her right hand. On reverse side of ref314. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4439; Zangaki Brothers (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Jewelry; Women; Individual Portraits; Head Covers/Veils
- Woman in national dress with hijab and a niqab. The woman carries a naked child on her left shoulder, the child's head resting on hers. On reverse side of ref313. 29.9 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 4440; Studio Photo Varjabedian, Zagazig, Egypt (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Egypt; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Painted Backdrops; Children; Regional/National Dress; Women
- Woman with flowers in her hair in a long light-colored dress with floral embroidery. 29.4 x 19.5 cm, Undated; 4441; Studio Photo Abel, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Jewelry; Embroidery; Women; Furnishings; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Individual Portraits
- 427 - Danseuse (Egyptian dancer). 30 x 23.7 cm, Circa 1885-1900; 9775; Studio G. Lekegian & Co, Opposite Shepheard's Hotel, Esbekieh, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Belly Dancers; Regional/National Dress; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Women; Cairo, Egypt; Dancing
- 30? - A woman leaning on a clay urn, posing against a painted backdrop. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated; 9776; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Painted Backdrops; Turkey; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Regional/National Dress; Women; Head Covers/Veils
- 1116 - A studio portrait of two bare-breasted women seated together. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated; 9777; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Group Portraits; Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Jewelry; Regional/National Dress; Women; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- A woman holding a baby in her lap, wearing a loose veil and beaded necklace. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Undated; 9778; Studio G. Lekegian & Co, Opposite Shepheard's Hotel, Esbekieh, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Cairo, Egypt; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Jewelry; Children; Women; Group Portraits
- A woman wearing an ornate face veil. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, 9779; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Niqab; Head Covers/Veils; Individual Portraits; Women; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils
- An vendor of sugarcane, a man with a waterskin and a girl leaning out of the mashrabiya. 30.0 x 23.7 cm, Circa 1890; 9780; Studio G. Lekegian & Co, Opposite Shepheard's Hotel, Esbekieh, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Street Vendors; Group Portraits; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Architecture
- A studio portrait of a man with a mustache and beard, wearing glasses. 29.7 x 23.6 cm, Undated; 9781; Studio Phebus, Grand Rue de Pera No. 301, au-deasus de la Maison Flament, Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Men
- A river with a stone bridge crossing it and mountains in the background. 27.1 x 33.0 cm, Undated; 9782; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Bridges; Rivers; Water; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings
- A group of women and men sit around a restaurant table, others look on from a window in the background. 27.7 x 33.5 cm, Circa 1930-1932; 9783; Studio - Jean Weinberg, Pera-Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Group Portraits; Restaurants/bars; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Istanbul, Turkey; Hats; Drinks/Beverages; Flags; Food; Jewelry; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Women; Facial Hair; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses
- A row of Corinthian columns supporting arches (linked ref332 and ref333). 27.8 x 35.2 cm, Undated; 9784; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- A view of a stucco ceiling, lined by Corinthian columns (linked ref331 and ref333). 35.3 x 27.8 cm, Undated; 9785; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations
- A colonnade of Corinthian columns at the edge of a temple (linked ref331 and ref332). 27.9 x 35.2 cm, Undated; 9786; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
- The ruins of a basilica. 28.0 x 35.1 cm, Undated; 9787; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Churches; Architecture; Religious Sites
- 224 - Mosque of Omar. Omar Moschee. Mosquee d'Omar. 27.9 x 36.1 cm, Circa 1898-1914; 9788; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Palestine; Jerusalem; Architecture; Religious Sites; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; German Writing; French Writing; English Writing; Photographic Prints; Buildings
- Ruins of a temple with Corinthian columns. 27.9 x 35.1 cm, Undated; 9789; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Temples; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Unknown Locations; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
- 109 - Le Fort Pharos (Citadel of Qaitbay). 27.9 x 35.2 cm, Circa 1870-1889; 9790; Luigi, Fiorillo (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Mediterranean Sea; Buildings; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles; Alexandria, Egypt
- Cyprus, Famagosta (Porta da Mar, Famagusta, marble from the ancient town of Salamis, inscription dated 1496). 35.2 x 27.9 cm, Undated; 9791; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Cyprus; Italian Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles; Forts/Castles; Famagusta, Cyprus
- A studio portrait of a baby propped up on a rattan chair. 10.3 x 6.5 cm, Circa 1860-1870; 9792; Studio - Anastasios Sklavounos, photorapher (ΑΝΑΣΤΑΣΙΟΣ ΣΚΛΑΒΟΥΝΟΣ. ΦΩΤΟΓΡΑΦΟΣ) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Greece; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Children; Greek Writing; Ottoman Writing; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card
- A studio portrait of a girl wearing button-up boots. 10.5 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 9793; Raphael Khendamian (Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Girls; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Individual Portraits; Children
- A studio portrait of a girl wearing a dress with a lace collar. 10.4 x 6.5 cm, Undated; 9794; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Individual Portraits; Children; Girls
- A studio portrait of a young man wearing a double-breasted uniform with brass buttons. 10.2 x 6.3 cm, Undated; 9795; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Uniforms; Fezes/Tarbouches; Ottoman Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; Facial Hair
- A studio portrait of a woman a coat with asymmetric fastening (same image as ref344). 10.5 x 6.8 cm, Undated; 9796; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Women
- A studio portrait of a woman a coat with asymmetric fastening (same image as ref343). 10.5 x 6.8 cm, Undated; 9797; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Individual Portraits; Women
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a military uniform and glasses, text on reverse "artillery lieutenant". 11.0 x 7.0 cm, Undated; 9798; D. Michailides, Andrinople (Edirne, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Swords/Knives; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Hats; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Individual Portraits; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Edirne, Turkey; Turkish Writing; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches; Weapons
- A young woman looking off-camera, wearing a blouse with an embroidered collar. 13.8 x 8.9 cm, January 1913; 9799; Studio - Photo Simon, 414 Grande Rue Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Women; German Writing; Constantinople; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a three-piece suit and glasses. 13.5 x 8.6 cm, Undated; 9800; Studio - Constantinides, Place du Tunnel 517, Pera (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Individual Portraits; Eye Glasses/Sunglasses; Men; Studio Photography; Istanbul, Turkey; Signatures; Facial Hair; Greek Writing
- A portrait of a man wearing a uniform and a young girl. 16.4 x 10.6 cm, Undated; 9801; Studio - G. Glikeas (Glykias), Phener Rue Balat, Sokak Apti Sou-Bashi no 15, Constantiople (Balat, Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Balat, Istanbul, Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Fezes/Tarbouches; Girls; Children; Men; Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- A food vendor by the banks of the Bosphorus. 14.4 x 18.7 cm, Circa 1896; 9802; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Dogs; Animals; Cattle/Cows; Street Vendors; Bosphorus; Boats/Ships; Umbrellas/Parasols; Hats; Fezes/Tarbouches; Food; Constantinople; Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Buildings; Facial Hair; Transportation; Water
- Four men standing in front of a steam locomotive, with a shoreline running alongside the tracks. 19.0 x 25.2 cm, Undated; 9803; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Boats/Ships; Group Portraits; Men; Railways; Trains; Coast; Uniforms; Transportation; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- Complex of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaytbay and the surrounding Northern Cemetery (City of the Dead). 21.2 x 27.1 cm, Undated; 9804; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tombs; Cemeteries; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque and Tomb of Sultan al-Ashraf Qaitbay; Mosques; Men; Religious Sites
- A studio portrait of a man with two young girls, one wears a dress with an anchor motif. 17.5 x 10.5 cm, Undated; 9805; Studio G. Lekegian & Co, Opposite Shepheard's Hotel, Esbekieh, Cairo (Egypt) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Fezes/Tarbouches; Hats; Children; Girls; Men; Cairo, Egypt; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- A studio portrait of a woman leaning on an ornate chair. 21.0 x 10.9 cm, Circa 1910; 9806; Studio - Photo Simon, 414 Grande Rue Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Furnishings; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- The 'shadırvan' (ablution fountain) of the Yeni Cami (New Mosque). 21.1 x 27.0 cm, Undated; 9807; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; New Mosque / Yeni Cami; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; New Mosque / Yeni Cami; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites; Fountains
- The military barracks and coastline of Izmir. 19.7 x 25.6 cm, Circa 1890; 9808; Rubellin, Rue Franque, Passage Psaro-Khan, Smyrne (Iznir, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Landscapes; Aegean Sea; Boats/Ships; Izmir, Turkey; Smyrna; Military/Soldiers
- Constantinople, Tombeaux des Sultans Mahmoud II et Adb-ul-Aziz (Istanbul, Tombs of Sultans Mahmud II and Abdulaziz, interior view). 20.6 x 26.2 cm, Undated; 9809; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Tombs; Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Tomb of Sultan Mahmud II and Abdulaziz; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Praying; Quran/Koran; Religious Sites; Individual Portraits
- Two bridges, one with a static steam locomotive on it. 19.0 x 25.4 cm, Undated; 9810; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Men; Rivers; Bridges; Railways; Trains; Transportation
- Men standing on either side of a railway track.19.1 x 25.4 cm, Undated; 9811; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Buildings; Railways; Railways; Men; Photographic Prints; Group Portraits; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Streets/Roads; Fezes/Tarbouches; Street Lamps; Facial Hair
- 279 - A studio portrait of two women wearing costumes. 26.7 x 20.4 cm, Undated; 9812; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Musical Instruments; Tambourines; Group Portraits; Turkey; Studio Photography; Painted Backdrops; Costumes; Women; Photographic Prints
- 342 - Dame Turque ..? (A studio portrait of a woman holding a shisha pipe). 24.9 x 19.9 cm, Undated; 9813; Zangaki Brothers (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Women; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Smoking; Furnishings; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Costumes; Regional/National Dress; Carpets/Rugs; Painted Backdrops; French Writing; Egypt
- 166 - Alexandrie, Boulevard de Rosette (now Sharia Fouad). 20.5 x 26.9 cm, Circa 1880; 9814; Luigi, Fiorillo (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Alexandria, Egypt; French Writing; Carriages/Coaches; Architecture; Buildings; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Street Lamps
- A studio portrait of a person sitting cross-legged, with their feet resting on a cushion. 26.7 x 21.9 cm, Circa 1880; 9815; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carpets/Rugs; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Costumes; Regional/National Dress; Men; Women; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Individual Portraits; Furnishings
- A studio portrait of a man wearing a morning suit and a buttonhole. 29.0 x 19.4 cm, 1896; 9816; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Individual Portraits; Men; Signatures; Painted Backdrops; Studio Photography; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Tuxedos; Flower Garlands/Bouquets; Turkey; Facial Hair; Bow Ties
- 102 - Mosquee du Sultan Ahmed (Sultan Ahmed Mosque/The Blue Mosque). 20.9 x 26.7 cm, Circa 1888-1908; 9817; Sebah & Joaillier, 439 Grande Rue de Pera, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Mosques; Blue Mosque/Sultan Ahmed Mosque; Buildings; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Fatih, Istanbul, Turkey; Architecture; Mosques; Religious Sites
- 2 - Obelisque de Cleopatre a Alexandrie (The obelisk of Cleopatra "Cleopatra's Needle" in Alexandria). 20.1 x 26.8 cm, Circa 1875; 9818; Pascal Sebah, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Architecture; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; French Writing; Italian Writing; Railways; Alexandria, Egypt
- A portrait of an Effendi seated at a carved wooden desk. 26.7 x 21.7 cm, Circa 1880; 9819; Abdullah Freres, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Facial Hair; Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey; Facial Hair; Studio Photography; Fezes/Tarbouches; Pens/Inkwells; Carpets/Rugs; Furnishings; Bow Ties; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
- 36 - Grande Cimetiere d'Eyouh (Eyüp Cemetery). 18.7 x 24.6 cm, Undated; 9820; Iranian, Mihran, Active circa 1890-1900 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Women; Tombs; Eyup, Istanbul, Turkey; Cemeteries; French Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Children; Boys; Religious Sites
- 20 - Porte de Seraskerat (gate of the ministry of War, now the entrance to Istanbul University and Beyazıt Tower). 18.7 x 24.6 cm, Circa 1900; 9821; Iranian, Mihran, Active circa 1890-1900 (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Architecture; Istanbul University; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Beyazit Tower; Beyazit Square, Istanbul, Turkey; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Men; Group Portraits; Facial Hair; Fezes/Tarbouches
- A portrait of Artin Miskoyian. 24 x 15.9 cm, 6 May 1930; 9822; Studio - Jean Weinberg, Pera-Constantinople (Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Carte de Visite/Cabinet Card; English Writing; Turkish Writing; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Facial Hair; Individual Portraits; Handkerchiefs /Pocket Squares; Facial Hair; Bow Ties; Tuxedos; Men; Istanbul, Turkey
- A woman in elaborate Turkish dress posing with a nargileh. 24.1 x 19.7 cm, Circa 1860; 9823; Rubellin, Rue Franque, Passage Psaro-Khan, Smyrne (Iznir, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Smyrna; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Photographic Prints; Head Covers/Veils; Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Shisha/Hookah/Nargiles; Individual Portraits; Women; Izmir, Turkey
- Photography teachers at the Imperial Engineering College. 17.9 x 23.9 cm, Circa 1890; 9831; Akozer, Ali Sami (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Istanbul, Turkey; Painted Backdrops; Uniforms; Studio Photography; Fezes/Tarbouches; Teachers; Universities; Men; Cameras; Group Portraits; Facial Hair
- Mustafa Celaleddin Bey wearing medals and posing on a bicycle., Undated; 9832; J. Gamlier, Grande Rue du Vardor 17 (Thessaloniki, Greece) (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Albumen Prints; Studio Photography; Individual Portraits; Men; Thessaloniki, Greece; Besiktas, Istanbul, Turkey; Turkish Writing; Bicycles/Tricycles; Photographic Prints
- A group portrait of men wearing uniforms and holding swords. 26.6 x 32.6 cm, Undated; 9840; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Fezes/Tarbouches; Uniforms; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Turkey; Men; Group Portraits; Swords/Knives; Facial Hair
- Workers surrounding a building covered with scaffolding 25 x 33.2 cm, Undated; 9841; Raphael Khendamian (Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey) (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Men; Horses; Carriages/Coaches; Animals; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Kadikoy, Istanbul, Turkey; Ottoman Writing; Buildings; Architecture; Construction; Workers; Mountains/Hills
- A group portrait of men wearing military uniforms with binoculars. 25.6 x 29.9 cm, Undated; 9842; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Turkey; Guns; Binoculars; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Weapons; Facial Hair; Medals/Insignia
- A group portrait of men in military uniforms with cannonballs in the foreground., Undated; 9843; Unknown (Box 6, Oversize unknown container)
  Boys; Turkey; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Medals/Insignia; Hats; Group Portraits; Maritime/Nautical Outfits; Bow Ties; Military/Soldiers; Uniforms; Swords/Knives; Cannons; Weapons